Guide to the Abraham Joshua Heschel Papers, 1880, 1919-1998 and undated RL.10086
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1880, 1921-1990s and undated; 6; 245 Boxes
  - Books, circa 1930s-1990s and undated; 9
    - A Passion for Truth, circa 1960s-1970s; 1
      - To be prepared, general, 1969, 1972; 1 of 4 (Box 103, Folder 3)
        A mix of annotated typescripts and handwritten notes, many of which are related to the Kotzk and Kierkegaard, presumably for A Passion for Truth. Includes a few student typescripts including "The Two Covenants and the Dilemmas of Christology" written by J. Coert Rylaarsdam, a thesis proposal about Heschel by S. Daniel Breslauer and a copy of "Prophecy According to Moses Maimonides and Abraham Joshua Heschel by Harold Kasmow. Also includes correspondence and an unedited transcript of remarks that Heschel gave at a B'nai B'rith Commission meeting
      - To be prepared, general, 1969, 1972; 2 of 4 (Box 103, Folder 4)
      - To be prepared, general, 1969, 1972; 4 of 4 (Box 103, Folder 5)
      - To be prepared, general, 1969, 1972; 3 of 4 (Box 103, Folder 6)
      - I, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 103, Folder 7)
        Primarily photocopied typescripts with some annotations related to the Kotzker and Hasidism. Materials likely a preliminary draft for Part I of A Passion for Truth. Also includes handwritten table of contents indicating which parts were ready or in preparation.
      - II B, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 103, Folder 8)
        Lightly corrected partial typescript of Part II of A Passion for Truth.
      - II Used, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 103, Folder 9)
        Lightly corrected typescript of Part II of A Passion for Truth.
      - III, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 103, Folder 10)
        Heavily corrected typescript of Part III of A Passion for Truth. Also contains corrected section from Part VIII.
      - III, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 104, Folder 1)
        Lightly corrected typescript of Part III of A Passion for Truth. Also includes the original typescripts without the corrections.
      - III Kotzk Used 130-176, circa 1960s-1970s; 1 of 2 (Box 104, Folder 2)
        Heavily corrected typescripts from Part III of A Passion for Truth. Also includes the original version of these typescripts without the edits.
      - III Kotzk Used 130-176, circa 1960s-1970s; 2 of 2 (Box 104, Folder 3)
      - III Old Copy, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 104, Folder 4)
        Heavily corrected typescripts of a few sections in Part III of A Passion for Truth.
      - IV, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 104, Folder 5)
        Heavily corrected typescript of several sections of Part IV of A Passion for Truth.
      - V, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 104, Folder 6)
        Annotated typescripts regarding the Kotzker and Kierkegaard. Materials appear to be a preliminary draft of Part V of A Passion for Truth.
      - VI, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 104, Folder 7)
        Lightly corrected typescript of Part VI of A Passion for Truth. Notes indicate that the section entitled "Sex" was incomplete.
      - VI: 265-298, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 104, Folder 8)
        Contains photocopied typescripts of pages 265-298 of A Passion for Truth.
      - VII, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 104, Folder 9)
        Typescript of Part VII of A Passion for Truth with handwritten page numbers.
      - VII, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 104, Folder 10)
        Annotated typescripts regarding the Kotzker and Hasidism. Materials appear to be a preliminary draft of Part VII of A Passion for Truth.
      - VII B, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 104, Folder 11)
        Lightly corrected partial typescript of Part VII of A Passion for Truth.
      - VIII, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 105, Folder 1)
        Mix of annotated typescripts and photocopied typescripts related to the Kotzker and Kierkegaard. Materials possibly used in A Passion for Truth.
      - IX, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 105, Folder 2)
        Annotated typescripts regarding the Kotzker and Hasidism. Materials appear to be a preliminary draft of Part IX of A Passion for Truth.
      - IX, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 105, Folder 3)
        Mix of corrected typescripts, handwritten notes, and photocopies of citations and notes related to background research on Kierkegaard. Also includes partial draft of Part IX of A Passion for Truth.
      - IX, circa 1960s-1970s; 1 of 2 (Box 105, Folder 4)
        Lightly corrected typescript of Part IX of A Passion for Truth.
      - IX, circa 1960s-1970s; 2 of 2 (Box 105, Folder 5)
      - IX-X Battle Today, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 105, Folder 6)
      - X, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 105, Folder 7)
        Lightly corrected typescript of Part X of A Passion for Truth.
      - A Passion for Sincerity, circa 1960s-1970s; 1 of 6 (Box 105, Folder 8)
        Photocopy of corrected typescript for A Passion for Sincerity (A Passion for Truth).
      - A Passion for Sincerity, circa 1960s-1970s; 2 of 6 (Box 106, Folder 1)
      - A Passion for Sincerity, circa 1960s-1970s; 3 of 6 (Box 106, Folder 2)
      - A Passion for Sincerity, circa 1960s-1970s; 4 of 6 (Box 106, Folder 3)
      - A Passion for Sincerity, circa 1960s-1970s; 5 of 6 (Box 106, Folder 4)
      - A Passion for Sincerity, circa 1960s-1970s; 6 of 6 (Box 106, Folder 5)
      - [A Passion for Truth], circa 1960s-1970s; 1 of 12 (Box 106, Folder 6)
        A photocopy of an annotated typescript of A Passion for Truth. Some pages missing.
      - [A Passion for Truth], circa 1960s-1970s; 2 of 12 (Box 106, Folder 7)
      - [A Passion for Truth], circa 1960s-1970s; 3 of 12 (Box 107, Folder 1)
      - [A Passion for Truth], circa 1960s-1970s; 4 of 12 (Box 107, Folder 2)
      - [A Passion for Truth], circa 1960s-1970s; 5 of 12 (Box 107, Folder 3)
      - [A Passion for Truth], circa 1960s-1970s; 6 of 12 (Box 107, Folder 4)
      - [A Passion for Truth], circa 1960s-1970s; 7 of 12 (Box 107, Folder 5)
      - [A Passion for Truth], circa 1960s-1970s; 8 of 12 (Box 107, Folder 6)
      - [A Passion for Truth], circa 1960s-1970s; 9 of 12 (Box 107, Folder 7)
      - [A Passion for Truth], circa 1960s-1970s; 10 of 12 (Box 107, Folder 8)
      - [A Passion for Truth], circa 1960s-1970s; 11 of 12 (Box 107, Folder 9)
      - [A Passion for Truth], circa 1960s-1970s; 12 of 12 (Box 107, Folder 10)
      - B IV Kotzk, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 107, Folder 11)
        Lightly corrected typescript of Part IV of A Passion for Truth. Typescript is incomplete.
      - [Baal Shem Tov, Hasidism, the Kotzker], circa 1960s-1970s; 1 of 2 (Box 107, Folder 12)
        Mix of typescripts, annotated typescripts, and handwritten notes regarding The Baal Shem Tov, Hasidism, and the Kotzker. Materials likely used for A Passion for Truth.
      - [Baal Shem Tov, Hasidism, the Kotzker], circa 1960s-1970s; 2 of 2 (Box 107, Folder 13)
      - [Baal Shem Tov, the Kotzker], circa 1960s-1970s (Box 108, Folder 1)
        Photocopied typescript regarding The Baal Shem Tov and the Kotzker. Materials possibly used for A Passion for Truth.
      - שזנות BCD, circa 1960s-1970s; 1 of 2 (Box 108, Folder 2)
        Transliteration: Sh-zenut
        Translation: Prostitution/Harlotry
        Lightly corrected typescripts from various sections of Parts I and IV in A Passion for Truth.
      - שזנות BCD, circa 1960s-1970s; 2 of 2 (Box 108, Folder 3)
      - Bescht I 1-98, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 108, Folder 4)
        Heavily corrected typescripts of several sections of Part I of A Passion for Truth related primarily to The Baal Shem Tov and the Kotzker.
      - Defective, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 108, Folder 5)
        Annotated typescripts of A Passion for Truth.
      - [Dust jacket cover for A Passion for Sincerity], circa 1960s-1970s (Oversize-box 7, Folder 6)
        Dust jacket for A Passion for Sincerity.
      - Faith V, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 108, Folder 6)
        Lightly corrected typescript of Part V of A Passion for Truth.
      - Fulbright 1972-1973, circa 1960s-1970s; 1 of 2 (Box 108, Folder 7)
        Annotated working typescripts of sections of A Passion for Truth, mainly about The Kotzker and Kierkegaard.
      - Fulbright 1972-1973, circa 1960s-1970s; 2 of 2 (Box 108, Folder 8)
      - [Galley Proofs - A Passion for Sincerity], circa 1960s-1970s; 1 of 2 (Oversize-box 10, Folder 7)
        Galley proofs of sections of "A Passion for Sincerity" which became A Passion for Truth.
      - [Galley Proofs - A Passion for Sincerity], circa 1960s-1970s; 2 of 2 (Oversize-box 10, Folder 8)
      - KK - Used?, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 109, Folder 1)
        Annotated working typescripts and photocopies of annotated working typescripts used for A Passion for Truth. Loosely organized according to sections of the books.
      - Kotzk, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 109, Folder 2)
        Several lightly corrected typescripts on the topic of alienation from A Passion for Truth.
      - Kotzk, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 109, Folder 3)
        Lightly corrected typescripts primarily about The Baal Shem Tov, likely from Part I of A Passion for Truth.
      - Kotzk, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 109, Folder 4)
        A few corrected pages from Part VII of A Passion for Truth.
      - Kotzk, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 109, Folder 5)
        Heavily corrected typescript of Part II of A Passion for Truth.
      - Kotzk, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 109, Folder 6)
        Multiple corrected versions of "I Want Honesty" in Part IV of A Passion for Truth. Also includes some handwritten notes.
      - Kotzk, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 109, Folder 7)
        Lightly corrected partial typescripts with some handwritten notes of Parts I and IX of A Passion for Truth.
      - Kotzk, circa 1960s-1970s; 1 of 2 (Box 109, Folder 8)
        Handwritten notes primarily related to the Kotzker, but also includes topics such as prayer and Hasidism. Presumably notes for A Passion for Truth.
      - Kotzk, circa 1960s-1970s; 2 of 2 (Box 109, Folder 9)
      - Kotzk III, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 110, Folder 1)
        Corrected typescripts from Parts III and V of A Passion for Truth.
      - Kotzk III, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 110, Folder 2)
        Incomplete typescript of Part III of A Passion for Truth.
      - Kotzk V, circa 1960s-1970s; 1 of 2 (Box 110, Folder 3)
        Typescripts of multiple versions of Part V of A Passion for Truth.
      - Kotzk V, circa 1960s-1970s; 2 of 2 (Box 110, Folder 4)
      - Kotzk VI, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 110, Folder 5)
        Lightly corrected typescript of Part VI of A Passion for Truth. Typescript is incomplete.
      - Kotzk VII B, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 110, Folder 6)
        Lightly corrected typescript of Part VIII of A Passion for Truth.
      - Kotzk Old Copy VI and VII, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 110, Folder 7)
        Typescripts for Parts VI and VII of A Passion for Truth. Also includes typescript for sections in Part VIII.
      - Kotzker, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 111, Folder 1)
        Corrected incomplete typescripts from various parts of A Passion for Truth.
      - McGaw - עברתי - VII, VIII, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 111, Folder 2)
        Transliteration: McGaw - 'Avarti - VII, VIII
        Translation: McGaw - I went over - VII, VIII
        Corrected photocopied typescripts which appear to be partial drafts of Parts VII and VIII of A Passion for Truth.
      - שונות, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 111, Folder 3)
        Mix of annotated typescripts and photocopied typescripts related to the Kotzer. Include topics such as polarity, absurdity, ego-centricity and imagination. Materials possibly used in A Passion for Truth. Also includes a drawing from a child named Gina, and a one page galley proof in Yiddish from the book about the Kotzker.
      - שונות II, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 111, Folder 4)
        Mix of handwritten and typed notes presumably for Part II of A Passion for Truth.
      - P.2, circa 1960s-1970s; 1 of 2 (Box 111, Folder 5)
        Lightly corrected typescripts of several sections of Part I and Part III of A Passion for Truth.
      - P.2, circa 1960s-1970s; 2 of 2 (Box 111, Folder 6)
      - [Part I], circa 1960s-1970s (Box 111, Folder 7)
        Lightly corrected partial typescript of Part I of A Passion for Truth.
      - [Part III], circa 1960s-1970s (Box 111, Folder 8)
        Heavily corrected typescript of Part III of A Passion for Truth, which appears to be an early draft based on edits by Heschel.
      - [Part X], circa 1960s-1970s (Box 111, Folder 9)
        Lightly corrected typescript of Part X of A Passion for Truth. Typescript is incomplete.
      - פ"א, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 112, Folder 1)
        Transliteration: P"A
        Translation: [Part I]
        Incomplete annotated typescript regarding the Kotzker and Hasidism. Appears to be draft for several sections in Part IX of A Passion for Truth.
      - פ"א, circa 1960s-1970s; 1 of 2 (Box 112, Folder 2)
        Annotated typescripts regarding the Kotzker and Hasidism. Materials likely used for A Passion for Truth.
      - פ"א, circa 1960s-1970s; 2 of 2 (Box 112, Folder 3)
      - Prayer פ"א, circa 1960s-1970s; 1 of 2 (Box 112, Folder 4)
      - Prayer פ"א, circa 1960s-1970s; 2 of 2 (Box 112, Folder 5)
      - Sherwin:790-798, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 112, Folder 6)
        Annotated typescripts related to the Kotzker, presumably for A Passion for Truth.
      - Sherwin: Miscellaneous, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 112, Folder 7)
        Contains one photocopied annotated typescript page of A Passion for Truth.
      - Sherwin: [Miscellaneous], circa 1960s-1970s (Box 112, Folder 8)
        A mix of handwritten notes, photocopied typescripts and annotated typescripts. Includes annotated typescripts of A Passion for Truth.
      - Table of Contents, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 112, Folder 9)
        Various versions of the table of contents for A Passion for Truth.
      - The Kotzker and Job IX, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 112, Folder 10)
        Corrected and annotated typescript which appears to be an early draft of Part IX of A Passion for Truth.
      - [The Kotzker, Hasidism], circa 1960s-1970s (Box 113, Folder 1)
        Corrected typescripts regarding the Kotzker and Hasidism. Materials likely used for A Passion for Truth.
      - The Kotzker Today X, circa 1960s-1970s; 1 of 2 (Box 113, Folder 2)
        Corrected typescript from Part X of A Passion for Truth.
      - The Kotzker Today X, circa 1960s-1970s; 2 of 2 (Box 113, Folder 3)
      - Charney, 1970-1972 (Box 113, Folder 4)
        Mix of corrected typescripts (in English), possibly a draft for A Passion for Truth and some galley proofs of the Kotzk. Also contains a handwritten letter in Yiddish from David Roskies (Chair of Yiddish Literature at JTS) about the publication of one of Heschel's books.
      - [Miscellaneous], 1971-1972 (Box 113, Folder 5)
        Mix of typescripts and handwritten notes related to a variety of topics including a Statement of Purpose from a graduate student (Robert Waxler) and final exam schedules. Handwritten and typescript notes on the Kotzker for A Passion for Truth.
      - Preface, Sincerity, circa 1971 (Box 113, Folder 6)
        Handwritten notes and annotated typescripts related to Kierkegaard and the Kotzk. Materials likely used for A Passion for Truth.
      - II, 1972 (Box 113, Folder 7)
      - IV, 1972 (Box 113, Folder 8)
        Photocopy of lightly corrected typescript of Part IV of A Passion for Truth.
      - IV Used, 1972; 1 of 3 (Box 113, Folder 9)
        Multiple versions of heavily corrected and annotated typescripts of Part IV of A Passion for Truth.
      - IV Used, 1972; 2 of 3 (Box 114, Folder 1)
      - IV Used, 1972; 3 of 3 (Box 114, Folder 2)
      - V 236-262, 1972 (Box 114, Folder 3)
        Photocopy of lightly corrected typescript of Part V of A Passion for Truth.
      - VI Kotzk Used, 1972 (Box 114, Folder 4)
        Multiple versions of corrected and annotated typescripts of Part VI of A Passion for Truth. Also includes corrected partial typescripts of Part VII.
      - VII, 1972 (Box 114, Folder 5)
        Photocopy of lightly corrected typescript of Part VII of A Passion for Truth.
      - VIII 318-357, 1972 (Box 114, Folder 6)
        Photocopy of lightly corrected typescript of Part VIII of A Passion for Truth.
      - VIII Used, 1972 (Box 114, Folder 7)
        Corrected typescript of Part VIII of A Passion for Truth.
      - IX 358-421, 1972 (Box 114, Folder 8)
        Photocopy of lightly corrected typescript of Part IX of A Passion for Truth.
      - IX Kotzk 359-402 Used, 1972; 1 of 2 (Box 114, Folder 9)
        Multiple versions of corrected and annotated typescripts of Part IX of A Passion for Truth.
      - IX Kotzk 359-402 Used, 1972; 2 of 2 (Box 114, Folder 10)
      - X 440-468, 1972 (Box 115, Folder 1)
        Photocopy of lightly corrected typescript of Part X of A Passion for Truth.
      - Archive?, 1972 (Box 115, Folder 2)
        Mix of typescripts and handwritten notes related to a variety of topics including the typescript "Israel - The Record: A Critique for the 1972 Election" and agendas for Seminar Faculty meetings. Handwritten and typescript notes on the Kotzker for the book A Passion for Truth. Many of the notes have been crossed through with pencil.
      - Dust jacket cover for A Passion for Sincerity, 1972 (Oversize-box 7, Folder 9)
        Trial dust jacket cover with flap copy corrected in red ink.
      - Kotzk V Used, 1972; 1 of 2 (Box 115, Folder 3)
        Several corrected versions of Part V of A Passion for Truth sent to Heschel from Mrs. Charney. Some of the typescripts have been crossed through with pencil presumably indicating that it was retyped with corrections.
      - Kotzk V Used, 1972; 2 of 2 (Box 115, Folder 4)
      - [Miscellaneous writings], 1972 (Box 115, Folder 5)
        Mix of photocopied and annotated typescripts that are works of others. Also includes some annotated typescripts presumably from A Passion for Truth.
      - The Passion for Sincerity, 1972 (Box 115, Folder 6)
        Correspondence and summary of copyright and royalties related to the unpublished The Passion for Sincerity (A Passion for Truth).
      - Xerox III, 1972 (Box 115, Folder 7)
        Photocopy of lightly corrected typescript of Part III of A Passion for Truth.
      - X Used, 8/1/1972 (Box 115, Folder 8)
        Multiple annotated typescripts regarding the Kotzker today, sent to Heschel from Der Algemeiner Journal. Various revisions of Part X of A Passion for Truth.
      - Galleys Kotzk: Author's Proof A Passion for Sincerity, 1973; 1 of 2 (Oversize-box 10, Folder 9)
        Lightly corrected proofs for A Passion for Sincerity. "Sincerity" has been crossed out and changed to "Truth".
      - Galleys Kotzk: Author's Proof A Passion for Sincerity, 1973; 2 of 2 (Oversize-box 10, Folder 10)
      - Galleys Kotzk: Author's Proof A Passion for Truth, 1973; 1 of 2 (Oversize-box 10, Folder 11)
        Proofs for A Passion for Truth.
      - Galleys Kotzk: Author's Proof A Passion for Truth, 1973; 2 of 2 (Oversize-box 10, Folder 12)
      - Galleys Kotzk: Not Marked, 1973 (Oversize-box 10, Folder 13)
        Unmarked galley proofs for A Passion for Truth.
      - Galleys Kotzk, 1974; 1 of 3 (Box 115, Folder 9)
        Heavily corrected typescript of A Passion for Sincerity, pages 294-580.
      - Galleys Kotzk, 1974; 2 of 3 (Box 116, Folder 1)
      - Galleys Kotzk, 1974; 3 of 3 (Box 116, Folder 2)
      - Kotzk, 1974; 1 of 2 (Box 116, Folder 3)
        Typescripts of various sections of Parts II and IV of A Passion for Truth.
      - Kotzk, 1974; 2 of 2 (Box 116, Folder 4)
      - Kotzk, 1974; 1 of 4 (Box 116, Folder 5)
        Heavily corrected typescript of A Passion for Sincerity, pages 1-293.
      - Kotzk, 1974; 2 of 4 (Box 116, Folder 6)
      - Kotzk, 1974; 3 of 4 (Box 117, Folder 1)
      - Kotzk, 1974; 4 of 4 (Box 117, Folder 2)
      - I, circa 1970s; 1 of 2 (Box 117, Folder 3)
        Mix of typescripts, annotated typescripts, and drafts regarding The Baal Shem Tov, Hasidism, and the Kotzker. Materials likely used for A Passion for Truth.
      - I, circa 1970s; 2 of 2 (Box 117, Folder 4)
      - VIII, circa 1970s; 1 of 3 (Box 117, Folder 5)
        Contains typescripts of Parts IV and VIII of A Passion for Truth. Typescripts are not in order and in some cases are duplicates.
      - VIII, circa 1970s; 2 of 3 (Box 117, Folder 6)
      - VIII, circa 1970s; 3 of 3 (Box 117, Folder 7)
      - X, circa 1970s (Box 117, Folder 8)
        Contains typescripts of Part X of A Passion for Truth. Appears to be at least two versions of the typescripts.
      - Charney, circa 1970s (Box 118, Folder 1)
        Mix of corrected typescripts and handwritten notes related to the Kotzk and Kierkegaard, possibly drafts for A Passion for Truth.
      - Mrs. Charney, Job A IX, circa 1970s (Box 118, Folder 2)
        Mix of typescripts and handwritten notes related to the Kotzk and Kierkegaard, possibly drafts for A Passion for Truth.
      - Giroux, undated (Box 118, Folder 3)
        Typescripts related to Kierkegaard and the Kotzk. Includes a table of contents. Materials likely used for A Passion for Truth.
      - בעל פה, undated (Box 118, Folder 4)
        Transliteration: Ba'al Peh
        Translation: Oral
        Primarily photocopied typescripts with some handwritten notes regarding the Kotzker and Kierkegaard, from various parts of A Passion for Truth.
    - God in Search of Man, 1951-1972; 2
      Published by Farrar, Straus and Giroux in 1955. Companion volume to Man is Not Alone.
      - Caine, 1951-1956 (Box 119, Folder 1)
        Mix of correspondence, press releases, reviews, and handwritten notes primarily related to the publication and promotion of God in Search of Man, but also includes materials for Man is Not Alone and the Sabbath.
      - RWS, 1951-1956 (Box 119, Folder 2)
        Press releases, correspondence, reviews, clippings, and handwritten notes primarily regarding the publication and reception of God in Search of Man. Also includes Heschel's own handwritten review of Between Man and God which presumably was retitled God in Search of Man.
      - 1952 (Box 119, Folder 3)
        Primarily lightly corrected typescripts presumably for God in Search of Man.
      - God in Search of Man: 560-700, 1952; 1 of 2 (Box 119, Folder 4)
        Annotated typescripts of God in Search of Man. Contains sections of Part III, Chapters 28-34.
      - God in Search of Man: 560-700, 1952; 2 of 2 (Box 119, Folder 5)
      - Lyons, 1954-1956 (Box 119, Folder 6)
        Primarily correspondence to and from Roger Lyons (of Pan American Broadcasting Company) regarding the promotion of God in Search of Man. Also includes several agenda for The Responsibility of Higher Education for Judeo-Christian Values in American Culture.
      - [Published works], 1954-1956, 1966 (Box 119, Folder 7)
        Primarily correspondence and some clippings related to publication and reception of God in Search of Man and other books written by Heschel. Contains letters from individuals praising his work, including Lotte Jacobi, and the article "Christ vs. Socrates" written by Reinhold Niebuhr for The Saturday Review.
      - Search Prepublication, 1954-1956 (Box 120, Folder 1)
        Correspondence, bulletins, and press releases related to the publication of God in Search of Man. Also contains a newspaper clipping in German celebrating the 80th birthday of Leo Baeck.
      - [God in Search of Man Dust Jacket], 1955 (Oversize-box 5, Folder 3)
        The original dust jacket from the first edition of God in Search of Man.
      - Behrmann, 1955-1956 (Box 120, Folder 3)
        Correspondence with Paul Behrmann mainly related to the publication of God in Search of Man.
      - RWS, 1955-1956 (Box 120, Folder 4)
        A mix of correspondence, handwritten notes, and event programs. Includes a number of letters from Roger Straus at Farrar, Straus and Cudahy, Inc. Publishers related to the publication and promotion of God in Search of Man.